Finding Aid for the Rudolf Carnap Papers LSC.1029
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rudolf Carnap papers
1920-1968
UCLA Library Special Collections
Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970
LSC.1029
32.0 linear feet (64 boxes)
Rudolf Carnap (1891-1970) was born in Germany. He was one of the developers of theories of symbolic logic (1920s-1930s), a leader in the field of logical empiricism and the first to apply mathematical logic to scientific language. The collection consists of correspondence, audio tapes of lectures, notebooks, literary manuscripts (some unpublished), corrected galleys, books, and periodicals.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Rudolf Carnap, 1968.
Gift of UCLA Department of Philosophy, 1993.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 997095813606533
Biography
Carnap was born May 1891 in Germany; Ph.D, University of Jena (Germany), 1921; instructor in philosophy, University of Vienna, 1926-31; professor, German University, Prague, 1931-35; professor, University of Chicago, 1936-52; was at the Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, 1952-54; professor, UCLA, 1954-62; appointed research philosopher, UCLA, 1962-70; one of the developers of theories of symbolic logic in 1920s and 1930s; a leader in the field of logical empiricism, he was first to apply mathematical logic to scientific language; his book, Meaning and Necessity (1947) was a pioneering work in the study of language and logic; member, American Academy of Arts and Sciences; died September 14, 1970.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, audio tapes of lectures, notebooks, literary manuscripts (some unpublished), corrected galleys, books, and periodicals.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence (Boxes 1-11).
Taped lectures on philosophy, Russian lessons (Boxes 12-13).
1993 addition (Boxes 13-21).
Articles by author (Boxes 22-64).
Philosophers -- Archives.; Online resources.; University of California, Los Angeles--Faculty -- Archives; Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970--Archives.
- Articles and Reprints
  - Abbagnano. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Abraham. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Ackoff, Russell L. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Acquaviva, S.S. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Adamic, Louis. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Addison, John West. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Alexander, S. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Allee, W.C. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Allen, Edward S. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Allen, Edward S. & Diehl, Harvey. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Allen, Francis. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Ambrose, Alice. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Anderson, Oskar. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Apt. F. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Anschutz, R.P. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Apostel, Leo. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Aristotle. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Artlet, Walter. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Arx, Max. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Aschenbrenner, Karl. (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Ashby, W. Ross. (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Aster, Ernst von. (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Atkinson, Richard C. (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Ayer, A.J. (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Bachelard, Gaston. (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Bachmann, Friedrich. (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Baer, Reinhold. (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Baidaff, Bernardo I. (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Ball, W. Macmahon. (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Bargmann, V. (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Barkhausen, H. (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Barnett, S.J. (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Barrett, L.G. (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Bartels, Hans. (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Barthel, Ernst. (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Bartlett, F.C. (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Bartlett, Francis H. (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Bartlett, M.S. (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Bass, Robert. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Bauch, Bruno. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Bauer, Franz L. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Bavink, Bernhard (1 of 2). (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Bavink, Bernhard (2 of 2). (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Beck, Eugen. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Beck, Maximilian. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Beckenkamp, J. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Begun, Reni. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Bell, D.A. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Beltran, Gonzalo Aguirre. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Benes, E. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Benes, Vaclav Edvard. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Benjamin, A. Cornelius. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Benjamin, Robert L. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Bennewitz, K. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Benrubi, J. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Berek, M. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Berg, Jan. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Berg, Otto. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Berka, K. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Berndl, Ludwig. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Berndtson, Arthur. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Bethe, Hans. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Birkhoff, Garrett. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Bisbee, Eleanor. (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Black, D.H. (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Blau, Julian H. (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Blondel, Maurice. (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Bock, A.P. (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Boenheim, Felix. (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Boffa, Maurice. (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Boll, Marcel. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bollert, Karl. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Bolza, H. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Born, Max. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Borner, Wilhelm. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Bornstein, Benedykt. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Bortolotti, Enea. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Bose, Raj Chandra. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Bothe, W. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Bougle, C. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Boutroux, E. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Bower, Gordon H. (1 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Bower, Gordon H. (2 of 2). (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Bramel, Dana. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Braunbeck, Werner. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Bronowski, J. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Bruman, L. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Bridgman, Percy W. (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Brightman, Edgar Sheffield. (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Britzelmayer, Wilhelm. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Britzelmayr. (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Brown, G. Burniston. (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Brown, J.F. (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Brown, Truesdell S. (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Burrow, Trigant. (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Byrne, Lee. (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Causey, Robert Louis. (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Chinese. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Chou, P.Y. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Churchman, C. West (1 of 2). (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Churchamn, C. West (2 of 2). (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Chwistek, Leon. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Dantzig, D. van. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Dartmouth Mathematics Project. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Deemer, Walter L. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - De Groot, A.W. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Dempe, Helmuth. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Deri, Max. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Dessauer, Friedrich. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Deutsch, Karl Wolfgang. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Deutscher Kulturatlas. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Dickson, Harald. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Diepgen, Paul. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Dieterich, Oscar. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Dilthey, Wilhelm. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Dingle, Herbert. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Dingler, Hugo. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Diniz, Almachio. (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Doblin, M.W. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Dodd, Stuart C. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Dorge, Karl. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Dorner, Alexander. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Dowdall, H.C. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Driesch, Hans. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Ducasse, C.J. (1 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Ducasse, C.J. (2 of 2). (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Dunham, Barrows. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Dyson, Freeman J. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Eddington, Arthur S. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Edel, Abraham. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Ehrenfest, P. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Ehrenhaft, Felix. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Einstein, about him. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Eklund, Hj. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Ekstein, Rudolf. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Elsasser, Walter M. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Elsbach, A.C. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Emch, Arnold F. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Emde, Fritz. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Emerson, Alfred E. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Endriss, K.F. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Engel, Friedrich. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Engel, Heinrich. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Engel, S. Morris. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Englert, Ludwig. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Enriques, F. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Epstein, Paul S. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Erdmann, Edmund. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Estes, W.K. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Ewald, P.P. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Fagot, Robert F. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Farber, Marvin. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Farrell, B.A. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Fassi, Salvatore. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Feibleman, James K. (1 of 5). (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Feibleman, James K. (2 of 5). (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Feibleman, James K. (3 of 5). (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Feibleman, James K. (4 of 5). (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Feibleman, James K. (5 of 5). (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Feigl, Herbert. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Feilchenfeld, Leopold. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Fein, Elihu. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Feitelberg, Sergei. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Ferguson, A.S. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Fermi, Enrico. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Fernandez, Carlos Graef. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Feuer, Lewis S. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Feynman, R.P. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Fick, R. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Field, G.C. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Findlay, J.N. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Fingarette, Herb. (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Firetti, Bruno de. (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Firth, Roderick. (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Fitch, Frederic B. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Fladt, Kuno. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Fleck, Ludwik. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Flesch, Rudolf. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Foster, Alfred L. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Foster, George Burman. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Fraenkel, Gerd. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Frank, Philipp (1 of 2). (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Frank, Philipp (2 of 2). (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Franke, Herbert W. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Frankel, Fritz. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Frankenberg, G. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Franzel, Walter. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Frei, Henri. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Fremlin, Celia. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Freudenthal, Hans. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Freundlich, Erwin. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Frey, Gerhard. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Fried, Milton. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Friedman, Murray M. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Fries, Carl. (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Fries, Horace S. (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Frizell, Arthur Bowes. (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Fuchs, Wilhelm. (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Funk, Paul. (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Furth, Reinhold. (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Gamow, George. (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Garcia Bacca, Juan David. (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Gardiner, Alan H. (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Garnett, A. Campbell. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Garvin, Lucius. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Gast, Paul. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Geiger, George R. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Geiger, Ludwig. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Geiger, M. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Geilen, V. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Geimonat, L. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Geiringer, Hilda. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Gellner, Ernest. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Gentry, George. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Gerard, Ralph W. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Gerhards, Karl. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Gerlach, Muriel Wood. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Gewirth, Alan. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Gide, Andre. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Ginsburg, Jekuthiel. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Ginzburg, Benjamin. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Giorgi, G. (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Glaser, Walter. (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Gleissberg, Wolfgang. (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Glocker, R. (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Gloden, A. (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Godel, Kurt. (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Gomperz, Heinrich. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Gonseth, Ferdinand. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Gorland, Albert. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Gotthardt, Gerhard. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Gottl-Ottlilienfeld, Friedrich. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Gottschalk, Louis A. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Goudge, T.A. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Goussinsky, B. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Graff, Th. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Gray, Dwight E. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Grebe, L. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Grebe, Wilhelm. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Green, Julian. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Grossman, R.S. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Grote, Fohr. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Gruneberg, Rudolf. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Guendling, Jack. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Gulliksen, Harold O. (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Gullvag, Ingemund. (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Guerard, Albert. (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Gumbel, E.J. (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Haag, A. (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Hadamard, Jacques. (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Haering, L. (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Haggstrom, Edith. (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Hahn, Hans. (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Hamburger, Leo. (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Hammer, E. (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Harms, Ernst. (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Harrah, David. (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Harris, Zellig S. (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Hart, Hornell. (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Hartig, Klaus. (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Hartnack, Justus. (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Hartshorne, Charles. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Hartung, Frank E. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Haskell, Edward E. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Hasse, Helmut. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Hassitzer. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Havas, Peter. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Haycocks, H.W. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Heisenberg, Werner. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Helper, W. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Hendrix, Gertrude. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Herbst, H. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Herrera, A.L. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Herrick, C. Judson. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Herzberg, Alexander. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Herzberg, J. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Hessenberg, Gerhard. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Heyde, Erich. (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Hiller, W. (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Hinshaw, Virgil G. (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Hirsch, G. (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Hirsch, Walter. (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - His, Wilhelm. (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Hiz, H. (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Hjelmslev, Louis. (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Hoberman, Solomon. (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Hocking, William Ernest. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Hoeffding, Wassily. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Hoensbrouch, Franz Graf. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Hoernle, R.F. Alfred. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Hofacker, W. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Hofler, Alvis. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Hofmann, Paul. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Hofstadter, Albert. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Hohenemser, Kurt. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Holm, Ragnar. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Holmstrom, J.E. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Holzapfel, Wilhelm. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Honigswald, Richard. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Horig, H. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Horn, E. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Hoselitz, B.F. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Hospers, John. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Hotelling. (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Huntington, Edward V. (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Hurewicz, W. (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Husserl, Gerhart. (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard. (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Hutten, Ernest H. (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Huxley, Aldous. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Huxley, Julian. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Ichheiser, Gustav. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Infeld, Leopold. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Ingarden, Roman. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Inge, W.R. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Irving, John A. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Isenberg, Arnold. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Isherwood, Christopher. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Ives, Herbert E. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Jackson, Reginald. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Jacobsson, Malte. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Jaeger, Gertrude. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Jaensch, E.R. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Jaffin, George H. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Jahoda, Eduard. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Jakobson, Roman. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - James, William. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Janek, A. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Jaskowski, Stanislaw. (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Jaspers, Karl. (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Jastrow, Joseph. (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Jeffrey, Richard C. (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Jeffreys, Harold. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Johanse, Svend. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Johansson, Ingebrigt. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, A.H. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Wendell. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Jollos, Victor. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Jones, Philip Chapin. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Jordan, Nehemiah. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Jordan, Pascual. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Jordan, Z. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Julios, B. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Juliusberger. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Kallen, Horace M. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Kaluza, Th. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Kamiat, Arnold H. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Kaminsky, Jack. (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Kamke, E. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Kamp, Hans. (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Kantor, J.R. (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Kaplan, Abraham (1 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Kaplan, Abraham (2 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Kappler, Eugen. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Kar, Robert. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Kasner, Edward. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Katkov, Georg. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Kattentidt, Ilse. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Kattsoff, L.O. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Katz, David. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Keenan, Joseph H. (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Keindl, Josef. (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Keisler, Jerome. (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Keller, Erich. (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Kellner, G.W. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Kelly, Chenault. (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Kelly, D.H. (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Kempski, Jurgen. (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Kent, Gordon. (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Kent, William. (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Kerler, DIetrich Heinrich. (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Kern, Bertholdt. (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Keyser, Cassius Jackson. (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Kierkegaard, Soren. (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Kirchberger, Paul. (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Kirk, John R. (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Kiss, Stephen A. (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Klamp, Gerhard. (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Klein, Lawrence R. (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Klein-Barmen, Fritz. (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Klyce, Scudder. (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - Kneale, William. (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - Knight, Frank H. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Knoll, Max. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Knudsen, V.O. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Knutson, John W. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Koch, K.R. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Koch, Rolf Albert. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Koch, Sigmund. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Koebner, Franz. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Koestler, Arnold. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Kogaloffski. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Kohler, Wolfgang. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Kohnstamm, Oskar. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Kokoszynska, Maria. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Kondo, Motokiti. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Konig, M. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Konvitz, Milton R. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Koopman, B.O. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Koopmans, Tjalling C. (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Kopff, A. (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Korgen, Reinhard. (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Korsch, Karl. (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Korth, Georg. (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Kortmulder, R.J. (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Korzybski, Alfred. (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Kossel, W. (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Kotschau, Karl. (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Kottler, Friedrich. (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Kozak, J.B. (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Kramers, H.A. (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Kratzer, H.A. (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Kraus, Oskar. (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Krauss, F. (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Kraus, Paul. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Kreisel, G. (1 of 2). (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Kreisel, G. (2 of 2). (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Kries, Johannes von. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Krikorian, Yervant H. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Kroman, K. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Kroner, Richard. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Kropp, Gerhard. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Kruse, Cornelius. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Kuhn, Ludwig. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Kuhn, Thomas S. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Kupper, Herbert I. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Kuratowski, Casimir. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Kuwakai, Ayao. (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - La Farge, Oliver. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Lafleur, Laurence, J. (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Laird, John. (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Lalande, A. (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Lamont, Corliss. (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Lamperti, John. (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Lamprecht, Sterling P. (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Lande, Alfred. (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Landsberg, P.T. (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Lange, Ludwig. (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Lange-Eichbaum, Wilhelm. (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Langer, Susanne K. (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Langevin, Paul. (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Lark-Horovitz, K. (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Laski, Harold J. (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Laue, M. (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Leake, Chauncey D. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Lecat, M. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Lederer, Emil. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Lefschitz, F. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Lehmann, F.E. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Lenard, P. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Lenz, Ernst. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Leontief, Wassily. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Lepley, Ray. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Leroy, Andre. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Lesniewski, Stanislaw. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Levey, Harry B. (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Levy, Solomon E. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Levy-Bruhl,L. (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Lewis, C.I. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Lewy, Casimir. (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Lichtenstein, Leon. (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Lieber, Lillian R. (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Liebert, Arthur. (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Liebig, Justus Freiherrn von. (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Liebmann, Heinrich. (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Liesegang, F. Paul. (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Linke, Paul F. (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Lins, Mario. (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Linsky, Leonard. (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Lipmann, Otto. (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Lobell, F. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Lodge, Rupert C. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Loedel, Enrique. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - London, Fritz. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Lorenzen, Paul. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Lorge, Irving. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Lossky, N.O. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Lotz, John. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Lovestad, Ludwig. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Lowe, Victor. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Lowinger, Armand. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Lowith, Karl. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Lowner, Karl. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Lowy, Heinrich. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Lubnicki, Narcyz. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Ludendorff, H. (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Ludwig, Wilhelm. (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Lukasiewicz, Jan. (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Lundberg, George A,. (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Lutoslawski, Wincenty. (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Lynch, J.A. (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Lynkeus. (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - McCabe, Joseph. (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - McConnell, R.A. (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - McCulloch, Warren S. (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - McGill, V.J. (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - McGreal, Ian. (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - MacIver, A.M. (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Maggi, G.A. (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Malik, Charles. (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Malisoff, William M. (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Mally, E. (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Mandel, Heinrich. (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Mandelbrot, Benoit. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Mann, Thomas. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Mannoury, Gerrit (1 of 2). (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Mannoury, Gerrit (2 of 2). (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Marbe, Karl. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Margulies, Max. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Marinelli, W. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Maritain, Jacques. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Marschak, Jacob. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Matchette, Franklin J. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Matheson, Gordon. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Matisse, Georges. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Matrai, T. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Matsumoto, Kazuo. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Mattick, Paul. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Matzat, Heinz-L. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Maverick, L.A. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Mayer, Anton E. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Mayer, Walther. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Mayeroff, Milton. (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Mays, W. (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Meckler, Lester. (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Medicus, Fritz. (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Melimke, R. (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander. (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Mellin, H.J. (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Melnitz, William W. (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Mendel, Bruno. (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Menger, Karl (1 of 2). (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Menger, Karl (2 of 2). (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Messer, August. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Metallmann, J. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Metzner, K. (Box 42, Folder 5)